{
	"name": "category-chapter-36-tag-vocabulary",
	"cards": [
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-36-tag-vocabulary-card-1",
			"front": "A rapidly fatal condition in which the walls of the aorta in the abdomen weaken and blood leaks into the layers of the vessel, causing it to bulge.",
			"back": "abdominal aortic aneurysm"
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-36-tag-vocabulary-card-2",
			"front": "Written documentation that specifies medical treatment for a competent patient should the patient become unable to make decisions; also called a living will or health care directive.",
			"back": "advance directive"
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-36-tag-vocabulary-card-3",
			"front": "A swelling or enlargement of the wall of a blood vessel that results from weakening of the vessel wall.",
			"back": "aneurysm"
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-36-tag-vocabulary-card-4",
			"front": "A disease that causes the arteries to thicken, harden, and calcify.",
			"back": "arteriosclerosis"
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-36-tag-vocabulary-card-5",
			"front": "An abnormal accumulation of excess fluid in the peritoneal cavity.",
			"back": "ascites"
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-36-tag-vocabulary-card-6",
			"front": "A disorder in which cholesterol and calcium build up inside the walls of the blood vessels, forming plaque, which eventually leads to a partial or complete blockage of blood flow.",
			"back": "atherosclerosis"
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-36-tag-vocabulary-card-7",
			"front": "Clouding of the lens of the eye or its surrounding transparent membranes.",
			"back": "cataracts"
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-36-tag-vocabulary-card-8",
			"front": "Sores caused by the pressure of skin against a surface for long periods; can range from a discoloration of the skin to a deep wound that may invade into bone or organs; also known as bedsores.",
			"back": "decubitus ulcers"
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-36-tag-vocabulary-card-9",
			"front": "The formation of a blood clot within the larger veins of an extremity, typically following a period of prolonged immobilization.",
			"back": "deep venous thrombosis"
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-36-tag-vocabulary-card-10",
			"front": "A temporary change in mental status characterized by disorganized thoughts, inattention, memory loss, disorientation, striking changes in personality and affect, hallucinations, delusions, or a decreased level of consciousness.",
			"back": "delirium"
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-36-tag-vocabulary-card-11",
			"front": "The slow onset of progressive disorientation, shortened attention span, and loss of cognitive function; this condition is generally chronic and irreversible.",
			"back": "dementia"
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-36-tag-vocabulary-card-12",
			"front": "Shortness of breath or difficulty breathing.",
			"back": "dyspnea"
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-36-tag-vocabulary-card-13",
			"front": "Any action on the part of an older person’s family member, caregiver, or other associated person that takes advantage of the older person’s person, property, or emotional state.",
			"back": "elder abuse"
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-36-tag-vocabulary-card-14",
			"front": "The assessment and treatment of disease in someone who is age 65 years or older.",
			"back": "geriatrics"
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-36-tag-vocabulary-card-15",
			"front": "The coughing up of blood.",
			"back": "hemoptysis"
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-36-tag-vocabulary-card-16",
			"front": "A visual bulging of the jugular veins in the neck that can be caused by fluid overload, pressure in the chest, cardiac tamponade, or tension pneumothorax.",
			"back": "jugular vein distention"
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-36-tag-vocabulary-card-17",
			"front": "A forward curling of the back caused by an abnormal increase in the curvature of the spine.",
			"back": "kyphosis"
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-36-tag-vocabulary-card-18",
			"front": "Black, foul-smelling, tarry stool containing digested blood.",
			"back": "melena"
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-36-tag-vocabulary-card-19",
			"front": "A bacterium that can cause infections in different parts of the body and is often resistant to commonly used antibiotics; it is transmitted by different routes, including the respiratory route, and can be found on the skin, in surgical wounds, and in the bloodstream, lungs, and urinary tract.",
			"back": "methicillin-resistant Staphylococcus aureus"
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-36-tag-vocabulary-card-20",
			"front": "A group of conditions in which the nerves leaving the spinal cord are damaged, resulting in distortion of signals to or from the brain.",
			"back": "neuropathy"
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-36-tag-vocabulary-card-21",
			"front": "A generalized bone disease, commonly associated with postmenopausal women, but that can occur in either sex, in which there is a reduction in the amount of bone mass, leading to fractures after minimal trauma.",
			"back": "osteoporosis"
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-36-tag-vocabulary-card-22",
			"front": "An abrasion of the stomach or small intestine.",
			"back": "peptic ulcer disease"
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-36-tag-vocabulary-card-23",
			"front": "An infectious disease of the lung that damages lung tissue.",
			"back": "pneumonia"
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-36-tag-vocabulary-card-24",
			"front": "The use of multiple medications on a regular basis.",
			"back": "polypharmacy"
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-36-tag-vocabulary-card-25",
			"front": "An age-related condition of the ear that produces progressive bilateral hearing loss that is most noted at higher frequencies.",
			"back": "presbycusis"
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-36-tag-vocabulary-card-26",
			"front": "A blood clot that breaks off from a large vein and travels to the blood vessels of the lung, causing obstruction of blood flow.",
			"back": "pulmonary embolism"
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-36-tag-vocabulary-card-27",
			"front": "A virus that causes an infection of the lungs and breathing passages; can lead to other serious illnesses that affect the lungs or heart, such as bronchiolitis and pneumonia. RSV is highly contagious and spread through droplets.",
			"back": "respiratory syncytial virus"
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-36-tag-vocabulary-card-28",
			"front": "A fainting spell or transient loss of consciousness.",
			"back": "syncope"
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-36-tag-vocabulary-card-29",
			"front": "An infection, usually of the lower urinary tract (urethra and bladder), that occurs when normal flora bacteria enter the urethra and grow.",
			"back": "urinary tract infection"
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-36-tag-vocabulary-card-30",
			"front": "Bacteria that are normally present in the human intestines and the female reproductive tract, but which can cause infection and which are resistant to the antibiotic vancomycin.",
			"back": "vancomycin-resistant enterococci"
		}
	],
	"category": {
		"value": "chapter-36",
		"label": "Chapter 36"
	},
	"tags": [
		{
			"value": "vocabulary",
			"label": "Vocabulary"
		}
	]
}